<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Polarization and Political Trust</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Polarization and Political Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:15:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Political Parties Crosswalk</title>
      <link>/post/political-parties-crosswalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/political-parties-crosswalk/</guid>
      <description>A new data note, authored by Marta Kołczyńska and Przemek Powałko, published in the journal Political Research Exchange, presents the Political Parties Crosswalk. From the abstract:
The Political Parties Crosswalk (PPC) maps party codes used in questions about party preferences in European cross-national public opinion surveys to Party Facts IDs, which are commonly used identifiers of parties in political science datasets. The PPC, a data linkage tool, supports research that combines data on party support from surveys with characteristics of parties, and in particular, facilitates research that combines data from different survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-project assessments of sample quality</title>
      <link>/post/multiproject-assessments-of-sample-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multiproject-assessments-of-sample-quality/</guid>
      <description>A new paper, authored by Piotr Jabkowski, Piotr Cichocki, and Marta Kołczyńska and titled “Multi-Project Assessments of Sample Quality in Cross-National Surveys: The Role of Weights in Applying External and Internal Measures of Sample Bias”, was published in the Journal of Survey Statistics and Methodology. From the abstract:
This paper examines existing methods of evaluating sample quality, showing that their practical utility and applicability to large-scale cross-project comparisons depends on whether they require auxiliary individual-level data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonization toolbox</title>
      <link>/post/harmonization-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/harmonization-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>This github repository contains resources for secondary analysis of data from cross-national survey projects, including ex-post survey data harmonization.
In particular, I collected survey metadata in form of data dictionaries or codebooks, from two major cross-national survey projects: the Eurobarometer and the International Social Survey Programme, which are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samping and fieldwork practices in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/sampling-and-fieldwork-practices-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sampling-and-fieldwork-practices-in-europe/</guid>
      <description>A new paper, written by Piotr Jabkowski and Marta Kołczyńska and titled “Sampling and Fieldwork Practices in Europe: Analysis of Methodological Documentation From 1,537 Surveys in Five Cross-National Projects, 1981-2017”, was published in the journal Methodology-European Journal of Research Methods for the Behavioral and Social Sciences. From the abstract:
This article addresses the comparability of sampling and fieldwork with an analysis of methodological data describing 1,537 national surveys from five major comparative cross-national survey projects in Europe carried out in the period from 1981 to 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Availability of political trust items in European surveys</title>
      <link>/post/political-trust-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/political-trust-items/</guid>
      <description>Availability across projectsAvailability across countriesThe first step towards harmonization is to learn which surveys have the necessary items - in this case about trust in different institutions: the government, national parliament, political parties, justice system, police, army, press, TV, and religious institutions.
This information, for 13 cross-national survey projects listed here, from 1939 national surveys from 39 European countries, is provided in this file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the project “Causes and Consequences of Political Trust: Polarization and Democratic Utility of Trust in Cross-national Perspective” is to advance the research on political trust by (1) developing a multi-level theoretical model of the causes and consequences of political trust that takes into account both the level of trust in society and its distributional properties, such as polarization, (2) creating a country time series of measures of political trust levels and polarization derived from existing individual-level survey data via Bayesian dynamic latent trait modeling, and (3) applying appropriate causal and multi-level modeling techniques to the newly constructed time series, as well as to the existing cross-national and panel survey data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>mkolczynska at isppan.waw.pl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data/</guid>
      <description>Asia-Europe Survey (ASES): https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/web/ICPSR/studies/22324
Candidate Countries Eurobarometer (CCEB): https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion/archives/cceb2_en.htm
Consolidation of Democracy in Central and Eastern Europe (CDCEE): https://search.gesis.org/research_data/ZA4054
Eurobarometer (EB): https://ec.europa.eu/commfrontoffice/publicopinion
European Quality of Life Survey (EQLS): https://www.eurofound.europa.eu/surveys/european-quality-of-life-surveys
European Social Survey (ESS): https://www.europeansocialsurvey.org/
International Social Survey Programme (ISSP): http://www.issp.org/
Integrated and United: A Quest for a Citizenship in an Ever Closer Europe (INTUNE): https://www.mzes.uni-mannheim.de/d7/en/datasets/integrated-and-united-a-quest-for-a-citizenship-in-an-ever-closer-europe
Life in Transition Survey (LITS): https://www.ebrd.com/what-we-do/economic-research-and-data/data/lits.html
New Baltic Barometer (NBB): http://www.cspp.strath.ac.uk/catalog2_0.html
New Europe Barometer (NEB): http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the project “Causes and Consequences of Political Trust: Polarization and Democratic Utility of Trust in Cross-national Perspective”.
You can learn more about the project and about the source data.
The project is funded by the National Science Centre under grant number 2019/32/C/HS6/00421.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
