<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>survey quality on Polarization and Political Trust</title>
    <link>/tags/survey-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in survey quality on Polarization and Political Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 16:07:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/survey-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multi-project assessments of sample quality</title>
      <link>/post/multiproject-assessments-of-sample-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multiproject-assessments-of-sample-quality/</guid>
      <description>A new paper, authored by Piotr Jabkowski, Piotr Cichocki, and Marta Kołczyńska and titled “Multi-Project Assessments of Sample Quality in Cross-National Surveys: The Role of Weights in Applying External and Internal Measures of Sample Bias”, was published in the Journal of Survey Statistics and Methodology. From the abstract:
This paper examines existing methods of evaluating sample quality, showing that their practical utility and applicability to large-scale cross-project comparisons depends on whether they require auxiliary individual-level data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samping and fieldwork practices in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/sampling-and-fieldwork-practices-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sampling-and-fieldwork-practices-in-europe/</guid>
      <description>A new paper, written by Piotr Jabkowski and Marta Kołczyńska and titled “Sampling and Fieldwork Practices in Europe: Analysis of Methodological Documentation From 1,537 Surveys in Five Cross-National Projects, 1981-2017”, was published in the journal Methodology-European Journal of Research Methods for the Behavioral and Social Sciences. From the abstract:
This article addresses the comparability of sampling and fieldwork with an analysis of methodological data describing 1,537 national surveys from five major comparative cross-national survey projects in Europe carried out in the period from 1981 to 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
