<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data availability on Polarization and Political Trust</title>
    <link>/tags/data-availability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data availability on Polarization and Political Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:15:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/data-availability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Political Parties Crosswalk</title>
      <link>/post/political-parties-crosswalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/political-parties-crosswalk/</guid>
      <description>A new data note, authored by Marta Kołczyńska and Przemek Powałko, published in the journal Political Research Exchange, presents the Political Parties Crosswalk. From the abstract:
The Political Parties Crosswalk (PPC) maps party codes used in questions about party preferences in European cross-national public opinion surveys to Party Facts IDs, which are commonly used identifiers of parties in political science datasets. The PPC, a data linkage tool, supports research that combines data on party support from surveys with characteristics of parties, and in particular, facilitates research that combines data from different survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonization toolbox</title>
      <link>/post/harmonization-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/harmonization-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>This github repository contains resources for secondary analysis of data from cross-national survey projects, including ex-post survey data harmonization.
In particular, I collected survey metadata in form of data dictionaries or codebooks, from two major cross-national survey projects: the Eurobarometer and the International Social Survey Programme, which are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Availability of political trust items in European surveys</title>
      <link>/post/political-trust-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/political-trust-items/</guid>
      <description>Availability across projectsAvailability across countriesThe first step towards harmonization is to learn which surveys have the necessary items - in this case about trust in different institutions: the government, national parliament, political parties, justice system, police, army, press, TV, and religious institutions.
This information, for 13 cross-national survey projects listed here, from 1939 national surveys from 39 European countries, is provided in this file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the project “Causes and Consequences of Political Trust: Polarization and Democratic Utility of Trust in Cross-national Perspective”.
You can learn more about the project and about the source data.
The project is funded by the National Science Centre under grant number 2019/32/C/HS6/00421.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
